





Los Angeles, CA



LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | Blog

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, React, Redux, Postgres, SQL, HTML, CSS, Git, Material UI, Bootstrap, Heroku, Netlify

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DJ Taylor

Education

Software Engineering Program

Flatiron School Online, 05/2021 - 10/2021

Bachelor of Music, Music Performance

Northwestern University Evanston, IL, 2006 - 2010

Master of Music, Music Education

Southern Methodist University Dallas, TX, 2012 - 2014

Experience

Music Teacher

Mayfield Junior School Pasadena, CA / 2019 - Present

- · Created and implemented innovative lesson plans for students in grades 3-8
- Introduced new curriculum and instruments based on drumming traditions of African and Latin American cultures

Music Teacher

University of Chicago Laboratory Schools Chicago, IL / 2016 - 2019

- Directed large instrumental ensembles for students in grades 6-8
- Advised a small group of students focused on social emotional learning and leadership skills
- · Developed a general music curriculum, including a project for students to build an instrument from scratch

Profile

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with extensive professional experience as a musician and educator. Possess strong skills in collaboration, project management, and creative problem solving that help teams work together to solve complex problems. Highly motivated to continue learning, passionate about building meaningful relationships, and driven to make a positive impact with my work as a full stack web developer.

Technical Projects

Bazaar - GitHub | Demo | Live Site

E-commerce application built using React and a custom Rails API

- Deployed app using Netlify and Heroku
- Utilized Redux and Thunk to manage state and asynchronous actions to the server
- Incorporated Material UI components and styling
- Utilized the Stripe API to handle simulated payments

Musical Musings - GitHub | Demo | Live Site

Ruby on Rails application for users to build playlists and share stories

- Deployed app on Heroku to use with students in my music classes
- Utilized the Spotify API to search songs, artists, and add song previews to playlists
- Implemented OAuth through Google

BrewLog - GitHub | Demo

Application for users to keep track of their favorite breweries

- Built using vanilla JavaScript and a custom Rails API
- Utilized the Mapbox API to enable users to search and save locations anywhere in the world
- Styled application with Bootstrap

Additional projects can be found on my portfolio website